有人吗
Hello!
帮帮忙
Help!
有人吗
Anyone?
该死 好...
Fuck! Okay. Okay, okay.
行吧...
Yeah. Yeah.
好了 你是谁啊
All right, who are you?
我为什么在这里
What am I doing here?
你为什么打我的头
And why did you hit me in the head?
有这个必要吗
Did we need that?
你是谁
Who are you?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你是法国人吗
Are you French?
有人要来跟你谈
Someone is coming to talk to you.
谁 谁要来跟我谈
Who is? Who's coming to talk to me?
见鬼 好 行吧
Fuck. Okay. Yeah.
谁要来跟我谈
Who's coming to talk to me?
你是不是拿了我的手机
Did you take my phone?
你是不是...等等...
Did you-- Wait, wait!
你能不能...该死的
Can you-- Fucking.
该死的
Merde!
该死
Shit.
(根据米克赫伦的著作《惊魂街》改编)
流人
第四季第三集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
大卫 再给你一杯茶
David, here's another cup of tea.
希望这一杯够浓
Well, I hope this one's strong enough.
查尔斯总喜欢喝很淡的茶 我就说
Charles used to like his tea so weak I used to say,
“你的牛奶里要加点茶吗 ”
"Do you want some tea with your milk?"
你记得查尔斯吗
Do you remember Charles?
大卫
David?
我杀了他
I killed him.
- 瑞弗 - 不对
- River. - No.
不 那是个长得像他的人 记得吗
No, that was someone who looked like him. Remember?
长得像他的人
Someone who looked like him?
天啊 我干了些什么
Dear God, what have I done?
大卫 那是正当防卫
David, that was self-defense.
不 我是为了瑞弗杀人的
No, I did it for River.
为了保护他 保护瑞弗
To protect him. To protect River.
他在哪
Where is he?
我的孙子在哪
Where's my boy?
他为什么把我留在这里
Why did he leave me here?
大卫
David?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是凯瑟琳斯坦迪什
I'm Catherine Standish.
我之前是瑞弗的同事
I used to work with River.
在那之前 我是查尔斯帕特纳的手下
And, before that, I worked for Charles Partner.
不...我不记得你了
No. No, I don't remember you.
你说你认识查尔斯
You knew Charles, you say?
- 对 我当过他的私人助理 - 我...
- Yes, I was his PA. - I--
后来我也当过杰克逊的私人助理
And then I was Jackson's PA.
炸弹
The bomb.
死了那么多人
All those people.
- 那些可怜的人 - 不 大卫 炸弹的事不怪你
- All those poor people. - No, David. The bomb wasn't you.
大卫
David.
- 我必须跟局长谈谈 - 你不能去总部
- I must speak to First Desk. - You can't go to the Park.
- 瑞弗不希望你去 - 不
- River doesn't want that. - No.
- 放开我 - 不行 大卫
- Get your hands off me. - No, David.
- 别碰我 - 对不起
- Don't touch me! - I'm sorry.
我必须和局长谈谈
I have to talk to First Desk.
我必须告诉他们发生了什么
I have to tell them what happened.
- 接下来会发生什么 - 会发生什么
- What's coming. - What's coming?
发生什么了
What happened?
炸弹袭击
The bomb.
瑞弗
River.
我必须...
I have--
我为什么要和你说
Why am I talking to you?
我记得你 你只是个小秘书
I remember you. You're just a bloody secretary.
- 把局长叫来 - 大卫...听我说
- Get me First Desk. - David. David, listen.
听我说 局长很忙 对吧
Listen, First Desk is very busy. Yes?
- 你是知道情况的 - 不
- I mean, you know what it's like. - No.
他们会跟我谈的 我以前可是负责人
They'll talk to me. I used to run the damn place.
我知道你是
I know you did.
但在每天的的这个时候 他在读柏林发来的电报 不是吗
But at this time of day, he'll be reading the cables from Berlin, won't he?
柏林 对...当然了 这...
Berlin? Oh, yes. Yes, of course. That--
- 他... - 时间表
- And he-- - The schedule.
对 他必须按时间表行事
That's right. And he's got to get that right.
有很多一线特工在待命呢
I mean, agents in play, awaiting instructions.
我们不能打扰
We can't interrupt that.
对...这很危险
No, no. It's very dangerous.
所以如果你允许 我会立刻给总部打电话
So, if you will allow me, I will call the Park right now,
然后我给你约个最早的见面时间
and I will get you the first available appointment after that.
你能做到
You can do that?
我是秘书啊 这是我的工作
I'm a secretary. That's what I do.
来 坐吧
Here, sit.
好
Okay.
- 好 - 这是你的茶
- Yeah. - Here's your tea.
谢谢
Thank you.
我马上回来
I'll be back in a minute.
- 你真好 - 不客气
- It's very kind of you. - You're welcome.
我得跟局长谈谈
I need to speak to First Desk.
好的
Yes.
是我的错
It's my fault.
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
谁在楼上
Who's upstairs?
平常那些吊车尾的
The usual bunch of dead weights.
这栋楼里 废柴们在楼上 精英在楼下
Shit rises to the top in this building with the gold at the bottom.
不过你的办公室在顶层 我收回刚才的话
Although, you have the top office, so I'll take that back.
听好 你这弱智 在过去一小时里
Listen, you tit, in the last hour,
有个人穿着你买不起的鞋走上了楼梯
someone walked up those stairs in shoes that are outside your salary.
是谁
Who?
不是我的错
Well, it's not my fault.
我不认识她
I didn't know who she was.
就算认识 我也阻止不了她
And if I'd had known, I couldn't have stopped her.
她进来的时候你在吗
Were you here when she came in?
不在 不是我的错
No, that's not my fault.
瑞弗是去拉旺镇了吗
Is River headed to Lavande?
去凯瑟琳家 叫她转移大卫卡特怀特
Go to Catherine's, get her to move David Cartwright.
大卫和凯瑟琳在一起
David's with Catherine?
那瑞弗呢
What about River?
这不在日程上啊
Well, this wasn't in the diary.
幸好我有空
Lucky I have a free slot.
有人给你倒茶或咖啡吗
Has anyone offered you tea or coffee?
- 没有 - 好 这样最好
- No. - Yeah, well, it's just as well.
好像有什么东西死在水箱里了
I think there's something dead in the water tank.
有何贵干
So, how can I help?
我想你知道我的来意
I think you know why I'm here.
你该不会被贬到斯劳部门来了吧
You've not been relegated to Slough House already, have you?
你干了什么啊 上班时喝酒被抓了
What the fuck did you do? Get caught drinking on the job?
你别装了
You can drop the act.
你看着像邋遢的傻瓜 但我知道你不是
I know you're not the shambling fool you appear.
验血结果出来了 对不对
Blood work come back, has it?
我能说什么呢
Well, what can I say?
他是我的特工
He's my joe.
他希望所有人认为他死了
He wanted everyone to think he was dead,
我就尽可能帮他装死久一些呗
and I helped keep it that way for as long as I could.
他虽然是你的特工 但也是军情五处的人 而且他曾出现在一个谋杀现场
He might be your joe, but he's MI5's agent and he was present at a murder scene.
也许他甚至扣动了扳机 我要把他抓回来
Maybe he even pulled the trigger. I'm bringing him in.
请便
Well, be my guest.
我不知道他在哪
I don't know where the fuck he is.
你大可用武力威胁我
So, you can put the thumbscrews on me,
反正我也只有这一个回答
'cause that's the only answer you're gonna get.
我要以妨碍调查罪逮捕你 起来
I'm taking you in for obstructing an investigation. Get up.
不了 我在这里挺好 谢了
Nah, I'm good here, thanks.
我还得无所事事一整天呢
I got a full day of fuck all to get through.
我即将呼叫一车特工来
Well, the carload of Dogs I'm about to call
他们可能会打扰你的清闲
might get in the way of that.
我可不希望人们认为
Well, I wouldn't want people to think
他们不得不派一群男人 来做一个女人的工作
they had to send a bunch of men to do a woman's job.
好了 手铐就没必要了吧 拜托
Now, cuffs won't be necessary. Come on.
我可不愿冒险 放任看起来像巴士色狼的人不管
I'd rather not take any chances with a man who looks like he gropes people on buses.
你对我外表的评价真伤人
You're being hurtful about my appearance.
我可能不得不向人事部投诉
I might have to call HR.
听着 我明白你为什么生气
Look, I get why you're angry.
你不得不对泰维纳说瑞弗死了
You would have told Taverner that River was dead,
结果她摆摆手 你就得回去跟她说
and she did a little jig and now you gotta go back and tell her
最麻烦的特工活得好好的
that the most troublesome agent is alive and well
而且不知所踪 鬼知道在做什么
and in the wind doing fuck knows what.
所以作为补偿 我愿意把大卫卡特怀特交给你
So, by way of amends, I'm happy to give you David Cartwright.
为什么
Why would you do that?
因为去总部就像进了宜家
Because going to the Park is like being in IKEA.
永远出不来了
You can never get out of the fucking place.
那带路吧
Go on then.
我的样子像个蠢货吗
Do I look like an idiot?
谈论你的外貌会给我惹上各种麻烦
You know, talking about your looks could get me into all sorts of trouble.
你愿意出卖大卫卡特怀特 来避免自己被捕
You'd burn David Cartwright to avoid being taken in yourself?
瑞弗是我的特工 但卡特怀特是个人渣
River's my joe. But Cartwright's a piece of shit.
一想到他被关在地下牢房里 我就爽得不行
The idea of him sitting in a basement cell stirs my nethers.
他在哪
Where is he?
嘿
Hey.
嘿 抱歉
Hey, apologies.
为什么道歉
What for?
我没意识到你是特工
Well, I didn't realize you were a Dog.
我是说 你显然不是走狗特工
I mean, obviously you're not a dog.
你把翅膀收在哪了
Where did you park your wings?
我是说你是个天使
Meaning you're an angel.
我怕你万一以为我暗示你是海鸥或乌鸦
In case you thought I was implying you were a seagull or a crow.
但你的腿这么长 更像是火烈鸟 对吧
But with those legs, you're more of a flamingo, aren't ya?
嘿
Hey!
我反正有女朋友了 所以你输了
Well, I've actually got a girlfriend anyway, so you lose.
我可以把手铐滑脱 所以...
I can just slip this off, so...
你又输一局
double lose.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
吉提 你是吉提吗
Giti? Is it Giti?
- 是吉提吗 是了 - 对
- Is it Giti? It is. - Yeah.
不 请...坐吧
No, please. Please, sit down.
请坐 这里没有级别一说
Sit down. No hierarchy here.
大家是个集体 我个人认为
All is one, I like to think to myself.
就是戴安娜泰维纳 把你推荐给了我 因为你...
It's just Diana Taverner commended you to me for your--
你调查“随时待命的身份”所做的工作
The work you did on the cold body case.
我想对你说非常感谢
And I wanted to say thank you very much.
谢谢 原来是个错误 真是大大松了一口气
Thank you. Such a relief it was a glitch.
是的...对
Yes. Yes, it was. Yeah.
不管让我们所有人都紧张了一下
Gave us all a bit of a scare though for a minute.
我无意导致任何不必要的恐慌
I didn't mean to cause any unnecessary panic.
不...完全有必要
Oh, no, no. Totally necessary.
我们必须探查任何可能性
I mean, we've got to explore every possibility.
其实这让我想 因为...
And in fact, that actually got me to thinking, because
我认为最好再查一次档案
I thought it would be a very good idea to double-check the archives
看看是否有其他错误
for any other glitches, you know.
“随时待命的身份”项目中是否有异常
Anomalies in the cold body program.
好
Okay.
我确实也是这样向她提议的
I did actually suggest that to her.
- 副局长 - 是吗
- Second Desk. - Did you?
她说我最好还是回来做当下的工作
And she said I'd be better placed on current duties.
是吗 好
Did she? Yeah.
当然 她说得很对 以她的立场来看
Well, she's absolutely right, of course. From her perspective.
她在负责一线行动 不是吗
I mean, she's running live ops, isn't she?
出了韦斯特艾克斯的事 她顾不上
And with Westacres ongoing, she doesn't have the bandwidth
怎么说呢 推测性调查这些事
for this kind of, what should we say, speculative investigation.
但我顾得上 我希望你直接向我汇报
But I do and I would like you to report direct to me.
我愿意
I'd love to.
- “愿意”这个词可能不合适 - 对 可能是
- Love is probably the wrong word. - Yeah, probably.
- 但她没意见的 对吗  - 对 这有点...
- It will be okay with her, won't it? - Yeah, that's a bit--
我不想惹上任何麻烦
I don't want to get in any trouble.
不会...此事就别让第三人知道了
No, no, no, keep this between ourselves, I think.
保密是一种优秀的勇气
Discretion being the better part of valor.
你会让我们提前避免可能的麻烦
And you'll be getting us ahead of any potential trouble,
这真的是帮大忙了
which would be a big help in fact.
如果有任何我可以做的事 来帮助实现这一目标
So if there's anything that I can do to facilitate that,
请告诉我
please do tell me.
你先请
Please, after you.
- 你之前来过这里吗  - 没有
- Have you been in here before? - I haven't.
- 你见过莫莉吗  - 没有
- Have you met Molly? - No.
她可有趣了...
A lot of fun. A lot of fun.
- 你好 莫莉 - 你好 黄鼠狼
- Hello, Molly. - Hello, Weasel.
“黄鼠狼”是指我们这些
Weasel's a term they use to refer to those of us
用游戏程序来精炼长期策略的人
that use gaming programs to refine long-term strategy.
就是这个意思
That's actually what that means.
你在我眼里永远是黄鼠狼
You'll always be a Weasel to me.
好了 莫莉 我是局长 好吗
Yeah, Molly, I'm First Desk, all right?
还用这个词不合适吧
Not appropriate, is it?
- 好了 随时待命的身份 - 是
- So, cold bodies? - Yes.
对 这是吉提 她认为自己 找到了一个和韦斯特艾克斯案相关的身份
Yes, Giti here thinks that she may have found one connected to Westacres.
我希望她再核查一遍
So, what I'd like her to do is to double-check that there aren't
没有老旧的随时待命的身份在被公开使用
any of our old cold bodies out there in the world being used.
你理解吧
You understand?
如果你能带她参观一下这里
If you wouldn't mind affording her the run of this place,
并尽可能地帮助她 那我就太感激了
facilitating in any way that you can, I'd appreciate that.
谢谢 非常感谢你 吉提 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you so much, Giti. Thank you.
我已经厌倦了局长和副局长之间的游戏
I've had enough of games between First and Second Desk.
对 我也是 很有意思
Yeah, me too. Well, it's funny.
很有意思 因为你觉得谁会赢
It's funny, because who do you think comes first in that?
我说局长和副局长的时候 你觉得...
You know, when I say First Desk and then I say Second Desk, who do you think--
戴安娜泰维纳
Diana Taverner.
娜塔莎
Natasha!
你是谁
Who are you?
你就是想跟我谈的人
Are you the person who's been wanting to talk to me?
拿着枪的人是我们 所以我们来提问
We're the ones with the gun. So, we ask the questions here.
好
Okay.
你看起来像林木区的人
You look like someone from Les Arbres.
你有一本有他照片的护照 而你不是他
You have a passport with his photo in, and you're not him.
你在那里做什么
What were you doing there?
我猜既然他一直拿枪指着我
I'm guessing from the fact that he keeps pointing that at me
你们应该不太喜欢这个人
that you didn't like this guy very much.
也许我告诉你们他无法再伤人
So, maybe he'll put it down when I tell you
因为他死了 他就会把枪放下吧
that he can't hurt anyone anymore because he's dead.
他为什么还不把枪放下
Why is he not putting the gun down?
他是我儿子
He was my son.
他怎么死的
How did he die?
他冒充我去了我爷爷家
He turned up at my grandfather's pretending to be me
因为他想把我爷爷淹死在浴池里
because he was going to drown him in a bath.
但我爷爷开枪把他打死了
But then my grandfather shot him.
这个结局是注定的
It was bound to end that way.
毕竟有那样的父亲
With a father like that.
听着 好了
Look, right.
我是军情五处的 明白吗
I'm MI5. Okay?
英国情报处
The British security service.
我们不在乎
We don't care.
你...走吧
You-- Just go.
是
Yes.
听着...
Look, look.
我很遗憾你的儿子死了 但我必须查清他是谁
I'm sorry about your son, but I need to know who he was.
我们叫你走 快走
You've been asking to leave, now leave.
别再拿枪指着我了
You really need to stop pointing that at me. Okay?
他们是谁
Who are they?
他们以为你是伯特兰
They think you are Bertrand.
是 可我不是伯特兰 对吗  你能告诉他们吗
Right. But I'm not Bertrand, am I? Can you tell them that?
- 你自己说去 - 我...好吧 听着
- Tell them yourself. - I'm-- All right, look.
听我说好吗
Listen to me, all right?
看见这个了吗 这个人
You see this? You see this man?
站你儿子旁边的
The one next to your son?
- 看见了 - 他之前也在林木区 是吧
- Yeah. - He was at Les Arbres too, right?
- 对吗  - 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
你们知道伦敦爆炸案吗 商场那个
Well, you know the bomb in London? The one at the shops?
他干的
That was him.
他引爆的炸弹
He set that off.
可能还会有爆炸案发生
And that could happen again.
所以你们得告诉我这些人是谁
So, you need to tell me who these people are
我在哪能找到他们
and where I can find them.
凯瑟琳 我是路易莎 又是我
Catherine, it's Louisa. Again.
新的特工头子艾玛弗莱特正往你家去呢
Emma Flyte, new head Dog, is on her way to you.
她要抓大卫卡特怀特 你得把他弄出去 趁她...
She's after David Cartwright. You need to get him out before she--
该死
Oh, shit.
不好意思
Excuse me?
打扰了 嗨
Excuse me? Hi.
真对不起 但好像有人跟踪我
I'm really sorry, but I think someone's following me.
你能陪我走到街尾吗
Do you think you could just walk with me to the end of the road?
我没看见有人啊
I can't see anyone.
那人可能藏起来了
They're probably hiding.
我...刚才在商店里 出来后
I just-- I was in the shop earlier and I came back out,
我以为他走了 但他又紧跟着我
and I thought he had disappeared, but then he was right behind me again.
不是他吧
Not him, is it?
不是 那个人...年轻得多
No. This guy is just-- He's much younger.
他的眼睛很可怕 他很危险
He's got really scary eyes, and he's just really dangerous.
好吧 你走运了 因为我是情报部门的
Okay. Well, you're in luck, 'cause I'm with the security services.
谢天谢地 能走了吗
Thank God. Can we walk?
- 我的同事会处理的 - 好
- My colleague will deal with it. - Okay.
- 太好了 谢谢 - 好
- Great. Thank you. - Okay.
- 一切可好  - 还好...
- Is everything all right? - Yeah. Yeah,
我刚才在跟你的同事聊
I was just speaking to your colleague.
我以为有人跟踪我 但看来没有
I thought someone was following me, but they're not.
- 所以是... - 你确定
- So, it's all-- - You sure?
- 确定 谢谢 老天 - 你看起来很眼熟
- Yeah. Thank you. Fuck's sake. - You look familiar.
天啊 你在女人遇到危险时跟她调情
Wow. Vulnerable woman and you're trying it on?
不 天啊 不是...我感觉我们在哪见过而已
No. God, no. No. I just feel like we've met. That is all.
好 你省省吧 趁我还没报警
Right. You just stop right there before I report you.
- 明白吗  - 明白
- Okay? - Yeah.
现在你要跟踪我吗
So now you're following me?
我只是想帮忙 天啊
Just tryna help, man.
我是艾玛弗莱特 总部的保安队长
Emma Flyte. Head of security for the Park.
请出示一下证件好吗
Can I see some ID, please?
- 有何贵干  - 你可以让我进去
- How can I help? - You can let me inside.
你有搜查令吗
Do you have a warrant?
你还是情报处的人
You're still a member of the service,
也就是说你受我的管辖
which means you're subject to my jurisdiction.
也就是说我不需要搜查令
Which means I don't need a warrant.
可我不久前辞职了
Except I resigned a while ago.
是 并没有
Yes. Not exactly.
你递交了辞呈 但文书工作似乎停滞了
You handed in your resignation, but the paperwork seems to have stalled.
提醒我一下 你还在拿工资吗
Remind me, are you still receiving a salary?
在拿 但没有花
Receiving, not spending.
无所谓 你依然在职 开门吧
Doesn't matter. You're on the books, so open up.
...韦斯特艾克斯爆炸案调查进展
...updates on the progress of the Westacres investigation
代理专员...
is the Deputy Commissioner...
看来你还在关注时事啊
Still keeping a hand in, I see.
我关注新闻又不犯法
I'm allowed to keep up with the news.
- 公寓不错 - 谢谢
- Nice flat. - Thank you.
这一带也很安静
Quiet area too.
你还喜欢读书
And you're a reader.
毁掉一本好书最快的东西 莫过于大量背景噪音了
Nothing spoils a good book faster than a lot of background noise.
还是不速之客更快
Unless it's unwelcome visitors.
- 说到客人 他在哪  - 谁
- Talking of visitors, where is he? - Who?
大卫卡特怀特
David Cartwright.
大...我有20多年 没见过大卫卡特怀特了 所以...
Dav-- I haven't seen David Cartwright in over 20 years, so--
请别进去
Please don't go in there.
他为什么会...
Why would he--
我叫你别进来了
I asked you not to come in here.
我不喜欢陌生人进我的卧室
I don't like strangers in my bedroom.
不好意思
Excuse me.
抱歉 这是演哪一出西区闹剧啊
I'm sorry, but are we in some sort of West End farce?
老天爷
Oh, for God's sake.
这门为什么锁着
Why is this locked?
没锁 只是比较紧
It's not. It's just stiff.
你必须轻轻开 否则就会这样 看吧
You have to open it gently or that happens. See?
我可能塞太多东西进去了
I've probably put too much in here.
听着 谁跟你说他在这里
Look, who told you he was here?
杰克逊兰姆
Jackson Lamb.
他叫你来一定是为了烦我
Oh, well, he'll have sent you here purely to distress me.
我们意见不合
We've had a falling out.
恐怕你被利用了 弗莱特小姐
I'm afraid you've been used, Miss Flyte.
稍等
Just a moment.
祝你早日找到大卫
Good luck with finding David.
你应该问问他的孙子瑞弗他在哪
You should try asking his grandson, River, where he is.
好了 我一会儿回来
All right. Back in a bit.
你也许该留着那支枪
You know, it might be an idea to hold on to that gun.
每个人都是目标
Everyone's a target.
韦斯特艾克斯案后 我们不知道 下一次袭击会发生在何时 何地
Post-Westacres, we don't know where or when the next attack will come.
戴上你的耳机 闭嘴
Put your headphones in, and shut the fuck up.
卖枪会遭报应的
It's bad karma to sell it.
还挂着圣诞装饰才会遭报应
It's bad karma to have the Christmas decorations still up.
武器流入街头和基于金属箔装饰品的迷信
Weapons on the street versus tinsel-based superstition.
还真是一模一样呢
Yeah, exactly the same.
听着 我也不想卖 但我别无选择
Look, I don't want to be doing this, but I've got no choice.
凯茜已经注意到未付的账单了
Cassie's already noticing the unpaid bills.
- 真是一场噩梦 - 你自作自受
- It's a fucking nightmare. - Of your own creation.
听着 我把这件事解决就戒赌
Look, I sort this, and I'm done.
这次是真的
For real this time.
嗨 你能下楼来帮帮我吗
Hi. Can you come down and help me?
滚蛋
Fuck off.
何需要帮助
Ho wants help.
除非是帮他自杀 否则我没兴趣
Unless it's with assisting his suicide, I'm not interested.
听着 我被铐在健身器械上了
Look, I'm handcuffed to my weights machine.
他被铐在健身器械上了 值得一看
He's handcuffed to his weight machine. Worth a look.
这是个意外还是你手淫的一个环节
Was this an accident or part of a wanking game?
是弗莱特干的
It was Flyte.
她真厉害
Good on her.
我就不问为什么了 因为我确定是你活该
I'm not gonna bother asking why, 'cause I'm sure it was deserved.
我说 你到底帮不帮我
Look, are you gonna help me?
不帮
No.
你干什么
What are you doing?
至少铐他一晚上 或铐到他拉在裤子里啊
I mean, at least leave him there overnight or till he shits himself.
我必须帮他
I have to help him.
你才不必呢
No, you don't.
你想知道我为什么要放了他吗
Do you want to know why I'm going to free him?
我想知道你为什么用匕首抵着我的喉咙
I want to know why you're holding a knife to my throat.
我被安排到这里之前
Well, before I was assigned here,
我被强行戴上手铐 绑在椅子上长达72小时
I was handcuffed against my will and tied to a chair for 72 hours.
所以他被铐着令我感到不安
So, I find him being cuffed triggering.
好 明白了
Okay. Got it.
你被铐着的时候发生了什么
What happened while you were handcuffed?
一个人威胁说要给我开膛
A man threatened to cut open my stomach.
他有一把电动...
He had an electric...
切割刀
carving knife.
厉害
Badarse.
手铐兄弟
Brothers in cuffs.
我不喜欢别人碰我
I don't like to be touched.
搞什么鬼
What the fuck.
维克多是我表哥
Victor is my cousin.
是吗
Is he?
幸会 维克多
Nice to meet you, Victor.
我被林木区的人搞大肚子时
He was the only one who stood by me
他是唯一支持我的人
when I was made pregnant by the man at Les Arbres.
那年我17岁
I was 17.
是这个人
And that's this man?
对
Yes.
弗兰克哈克尼斯
Frank Harkness.
不过他说了很多谎话 这可能不是他的真名
Although, he told so many lies, that may not be his real name.
他从不让我见我儿子
Well, he never let me see my son.
于是我搬走了 我时不时会回来看望伯特兰
So, I moved away and I would come back sometimes to see Bertrand,
但他当我不存在
and he looked through me like I didn't exist.
我们听说林木区的人都走了
We heard everyone at Les Arbres was gone,
她再也见不到伯特兰了
and she would never see Bertrand again.
我以为你是他
I thought you were him.
所以我给她打了电话 并跟踪你
So, I called her, followed you.
撞见弗兰克想要杀你
Found Frank trying to kill you.
然后你打了我
And then you hit me...
弗兰克为什么要杀你
Why would Frank try to kill you?
我认为他正在销毁证据 我妨碍到他了
Well, I think he was destroying evidence, and I just got in his way.
搞炸弹袭击的人呢
And the bomber, what about him?
- 伊夫 - 伊夫
- Yves. - Yves.
不意外 他小时候曾被虐待
Well, that's no surprise. The way he was treated as a boy.
你能看到他的憎恨 愤怒
You could see his hate, his anger.
所以你曾住在林木区
So, you lived at Les Arbres?
对
Yeah.
在伯特兰小时候
While Bertrand was little.
这是你画的吗
Did you paint this?
不是 其他那些女孩中的一个画的
No. One of the other girls did.
其他女孩
Other girls?
对 那些母亲
Yes. The mothers.
有些俄罗斯人 一个希腊人
You know, there were some Russians, a Greek.
可能有一个英国人 好像还有一个当地女孩
Maybe an English and another local girl, I think.
她们生下他的孩子 然后他就把母亲们赶走
They have his children, and then he makes the mothers leave
因为这是...
because that's--
他想要的安排
that's how he wants things to be.
我去跟他们说
I'll speak to them.
告诉他们你不是他们以为的那个人
Tell them you are not who they think you are.
好 有劳了
Yeah, please.
天啊 他们真是不喜欢你儿子 对吧
Wow. They really didn't like your son, did they?
伯特兰把那个人的儿子打进了医院
Well, the man out there, Bertrand put his son in the hospital
还袭击了他的女儿
and assaulted his daughter.
所以我们不怪他心存怨恨
So, we don't really blame him for his hate.
维克多会让他们冷静下来的
Victor will calm them.
- 见鬼 天啊 - 快跑
- Fuck me. Jesus. - Run.
这狗可真大
That's a big dog.
那不是他
It's not him!
他不是伯特兰
It's not Bertrand!
该死
Shit.
拜托
Come on.
先生
Monsieur.
好了 滚开
All right, fuck off!
搞什么...
What the fucking--
你为什么不接电话
Why aren't you answering your phone?
- 对了 你怎么样  - 手机在瑞弗那里 我很好 谢谢
- How have you been, by the way? - River has it. And I'm fine. Thank you.
兰姆为什么不告诉我呢
Why didn't Lamb just tell me that?
兰姆派你来的
So, Lamb sent you?
对 大卫在哪
Yeah. Where's David?
幸好我把他转移了
Luckily I moved him.
兰姆用了五分钟就想到了该去哪找他
It took Lamb all of five minutes to work out how to find him.
他比大多数人聪明
I mean, he's smarter than most,
但他不是惊魂街上唯一一个聪明人
but he's not the only brain on Spook Street.
大卫认为自己要在一个安全屋见局长
David thinks he's meeting First Desk in a safe house.
- 在哪  - 25号
- Where? - Number 25.
我在帮邻居照顾猫
I'm cat-sitting for my neighbor.
你见到瑞弗时 他怎么样
So, how was River when you saw him?
鉴于出了这么大的事 他还好
He's all right considering.
他拿着你的手机 却不接
He's not answering your phone.
他接不了 他把SIM卡拆了
He won't do. He's taken out the SIM card.
我很遗憾兰姆告诉你说瑞弗死了
I'm sorry Lamb told you River was dead.
你一定很难过
That must have been very hard.
对 基本上是最后一根稻草
Yeah, it's pretty much the final straw.
我可能会像你一样辞职
I might join you on the outside.
那你会感到很无聊的
You'd get very bored.
韦斯特艾克斯案有什么消息
What's the Westacres news?
没有
Nothing.
不过他们没排除还会发生袭击的可能性
Although they're not ruling out further attacks.
你知道是谁想杀大卫吗
Any idea who tried to kill David?
我只知道杀手来自法国
Just that they came from France.
你好 平克儿
Hello, Pinkel.
你对猫过敏吗
Are you allergic to cats?
不过敏 只是不太喜欢
No, I just don't really like them.
大卫
David?
凯瑟琳
Catherine!
后门开着
The back door's open!
天啊
Oh, my God.
糟糕
Oh, fuck.
我怎么跟瑞弗交代啊
What am I going to tell River?
我怎么跟兰姆交代啊
What am I gonna tell Lamb?
...才能得到自由
...will I be free.
我被你们的系统囚禁多年 你们将为此付出代价
You will suffer for the years I spent imprisoned by your system.
上帝自有安排 我不会是最后一个
God willing, I will not be the last.
你们很快会从我兄弟们那里听到消息
You will hear from my brothers soon.
我目前在...
I'm here on the...
韦斯特艾克斯购物中心外
...just outside of the Westacres Shopping Center,
这里的气氛依然...
where the mood is still...
恐怕有坏消息
I'm afraid I've got some bad news.
那是什么东西
What the fuck's that?
这个 只是个简单的小花束
This? It's just a simple tussie-mussie.
得了
Fuck off.
小花束啊
It's a nosegay.
在大瘟疫期间 人们会闻这些东西
People used to sniff them during the great plague
以此来消除死亡的恶臭
to cancel out the stench of death.
走开
Fuck off.
我问了我在总部的联系人
I've asked my contacts back at the Park,
没有一个证据表明 大卫卡特怀特曾去过法国
and there isn't a single shred of evidence that David Cartwright ever went to France.
所以我猜我们的交易取消了
So, I suppose our deal is off.
恐怕是这样
I'm afraid so.
看来我赶不走你了
Looks like I'm stuck with you.
不过我确实查到 他的传递员在1990年代初去过法国
I did discover that his bagman went there in the early 90s.
拉旺镇
Lavande?
对
Yes.
去找何 告诉他我发话了 叫他查清楚你为什么来斯劳部门
Go see Ho, and tell him I said to find out why you're at Slough House.
- 真的  - 真的
- Really? - Well, yeah.
对 我不想要你留在这里
Yeah, I don't want you here.
告诉我坏人山姆查普曼去过法国就足够了
And letting me know that Bad Sam Chapman went to France is good enough.
给 仔细看看
Here you are. Take a closer look.
你们确定没见过他
Sure you haven't seen him?
他就住在对面
He lives right across from here.
13岁 看起来要大一些
Thirteen. Looks a bit older.
名字叫KZ
Goes by the name of KZ.
你是说凯奇
Do you mean KayZee?
你认识他
You know him then?
看情况 有钱吗
Depends, is there money in it?
可能有
Well, there could be.
那预支一笔呗
How about an advance then?
我身上没现金
I don't have any cash on me.
我觉得你没有能告诉我的信息
And you know, I don't think you've got anything to tell me.
我们可以陪你去提款机
Well, we can walk you to a cashpoint.
我够丑的了 不怕被打脸 你呢
I'm ugly enough I don't mind getting hit in the face. How about you?
恋童癖
Paedo.
你好 麻烦鬼
Hello, trouble.
我要见面
I need a meet.
三号洗衣店
Launderette number three.
如果我有更重要的事呢
What if I've got something more important to do?
你没有
You don't.
我看着老头子呢
I have eyes on the old man.
好 干掉他
Okay, so take him out.
他正处于公共场所
He's in public now.
故意让他发现有人跟踪 他会紧张 试图躲起来
Let him know he's being followed. He'll get nervous, try and hide.
在别人看不到的地方动手 然后去杀卡特怀特
Kill him out of sight, then move on to Cartwright.
舞者布莱恩
Dancer Blaine?
给你准备了一件小商品
Got a bit of merchandise for you.
谁派你来的
Who sent you?
没有人
No one.
你怎么知道我的
How do you know about me?
我是军情五处的
I'm MI5.
这是在耍花招
Is this a sting?
我一上来就告诉你我是军情五处的 不算是耍花招吧
Not much of a sting if I tell you I'm MI5 from the off, right?
有道理
Fair point.
好吧
All right.
知道人们为什么叫我舞者吗
Do you know why they call me Dancer?
因为你喜欢在舞厅里跳舞
'Cause you're into ballroom dancing?
还因为我能察觉到危险并优雅地躲开
And also because I sense danger and dance right around it.
为军情五处的官员服务 我觉得会惹上麻烦
Now, serving MI5 officer, well, that screams trouble to me.
你为什么想卖给我一支枪
Why do you want to sell me a gun?
- 我需要钱 急需 - 那去抢银行啊
- I need money, right and fast. - So, rob a bank.
如果你不想收这支枪 没关系 我去别处卖
If you don't want the gun, fine by me. I'll take it elsewhere.
你不会的 你需要钱
No, you won't. You need the cash.
这是我叫舞者的另一个原因
That's the other thing about being a dancer.
我学会了看透别人 预估对方的行动
You learn to read people. Anticipate their moves.
我能看出你心地善良
And I can tell you've got a good heart.
但你走投无路了
But you're all out of moves.
贝雷塔M9
Beretta M9.
于1985年胜过了西格绍尔P226 成为美军的
Beat out the Sig Sauer P226 to become the primary sidearm
主要随身武器 直至今日
of the US Army from 1985 to present.
- 三千 - 它值五千
- Three grand. - It's worth five.
对 没错 我可以卖到五千 这就是赚钱的机制
Yeah. No, I can sell it for five. That's how profit works.
- 好吧 四千五 - 三千
- All right, four and a half. - Three.
- 四千 - 三千
- Four. - Three.
- 三千五 - 三千
- Three and a half. - Three.
- 三千 - 很好
- Three. - Perfect.
谈得不错
Great negotiating.
今年之内 你随时过来就好
Any time this year would be great.
有人跟踪我
Picked up a tail.
你在哪
Where are you?
带着尾巴远离你
Leading them away from you.
可能是因为我在查的案子 我在找一个13岁的孩子
Could be a case I'm working looking for a 13-year-old.
离家出走
Runaway.
惹上了不好的团体 我刚刚质问了其中几位
Got mixed up with the wrong crowd. Just faced some of them down.
- 可能是他们 - 不是
- Could be them. - It's not.
昨晚有人试图做掉大卫卡特怀特
Someone tried to whack David Cartwright last night.
该死 谁
Shit. Who?
我不知道 但老不死的用霰弹枪把他崩了
I don't know, but the old bastard blew him away with a shotgun.
- 有人来找你吗  - 还没有
- Anyone come looking for you? - Not yet.
我会去二号备用点
I'll head to fallback number two.
我叫下等马从市场开始跟着你
I'll have the Slow Horses follow you from the market
以防你的尾巴有所行动
in case your tail makes a move.
你给我回电了真好
Nice of you to call me back.
兰姆打过电话 他需要我们 为他跟坏人山姆查普曼见面做支援
Lamb called. He needs us as a backup for a meet with Bad Sam Chapman.
他说从市场开始跟着他 去二号备用点
He said to tail him from the market to fallback number two.
好 那是旧修车厂
Yeah, that's the old garage.
我正好离那里不远 好 我尽快过去
Actually, I'm not far. All right, be there soon as.
一定要带着枪来
Make sure you come packing heat.
不 你带不了
Oh, no. You can't.
闭嘴
Shut up.
雪莉
Shirley!
该死的 你还想引起更多人的注意吗
Fucking hell. Do you wanna draw any more attention?
查普曼在前方180米处
Chapman's 200 yards ahead.
好吧 尾巴在哪
All right. Where's the tail?
我以为我看到他了 但他消失了
I thought I saw him, but he's disappeared.
也许看到我来 他就溜了
Probably saw me coming and scarpered.
你的帽子把他吓跑了吧
I mean, that hat would do it.
该死
Shit.
- 你还好吗  - 不好
- Are you all right? - No.
该死的
Fucking hell.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我还好
I'm all right.
可恶
Fuck.
快接听...
Come on, come on, come on.
我似乎甩不掉他
I can't seem to shake him.
- 终止会面 - 不 继续走
- Abort. - No, keep moving.
- 我马上到 - 好
- I'll be there. - Okay.
出来吧 老家伙
Come out, old man.
结束了 出来
It's over. Let's go.
你们还好吗
You all right?
给 扶他起来 上德士
Here, get him up and in the cab.
我来处理车祸受害者
I'll deal with the roadkill.
字幕翻译:吴梦熊